

LU HTOO KYAW

MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER

CONTACT INFO

+95 9799899364

✓ luhtookvaw8798@gmail.cc

Iuhtookyaw.github.id

in linkedin.com/in/lu-htoo-kyaw-382347188/

No-29, Lower Mandalay St, Mingalar Taung Nyunt Tsp, Yangon Region

SKILLS

Machine Learning

Computer Vision I Time Series Analysis I Reinforcement Learning

Data Science

nferencial Statistics | Bayesian Statistics

Frameworks

PyTorch I TensorFlow I Sklearn I OpenCV

Programming Languages
Python | JavaScript | PHP | C++

Unix/Linux

CLI I Bash Scrip

Version Control

Git | Github Actions | DVC

Database

MySQL I MongoDB I SQLite

Frontend

React JS I Vue JS I Streamli

Backend

Node JS | Diango | Flask | FastAPI

Development Operations

LANGUAGES

English

Speaking | Listening | Reading | Writing

PROFILE

I am a Machine Learning Engineer, mainly experienced in development especially associated with Computer Vision, Time Series Analysis and passionate about all sorts of Machine Learning subjects. Being able to prove enthusiasm to take on any task to support the project team and enhance the team progress. Offer strong coding skills, vast knowledge of development materials, and confidence to overcome strict deadlines.

EXPERIENCE

MYANMA AWBA

On-site, Aug 2022 - Present

OMDENA

Remote, Apr 2022 - Present

SPARK FOUNDATION

Remote, May 2022 - Jun 2022

GEOSPATIAL MACHINE LEARNING RESEARCHER, INTERNSHIP

My tasks and duties are to perform various GIS and remote sensing operations for obtaining geospatial datasets and to research deep learning models fitted for those datasets.

BONDY: MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER, VOLUNTEER

Main objective was using AI to monitor trees during reforestation process in Andramasina district, Madasgascar along with 30 collaborators from over 20 countries. During modelling process, we used CVAT tool for manual labeling and unsupervised methods for automatic labeling to drone images which were then used in experimenting models such as UNet, UNet++ and DeepLabv3 to segment trees in the area. Inferenced drone images were later combined with OpenDroneMap software to achieve field level estimation of the area. We used Google Earth Engine to obtain Sentinal-2 images and extract NDVI time series for charting purpose. Finally, a dashboard was build with Streamlit to provide our client insights. My participation was mainly in model building but I also contributed significantly in data collection and pipeline orchestration.

DR-CADX: MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER, VOLUNTEER

The mission of the project was using AI to detect cervical cancer for women with inability to afford pathological tests in Africa, accompanied by 50 collaborators around the globe. We researched wide range of available datasets of microscope cytological image slides to build classification model corresponding with examining cells. We experimented some backbone architectures such as ResNet, RegNet, InceptionNet and VGGNet to extract feature representations so that they can be used in our custom-built neural architectures. I engaged a great deal of architectural researching and model implementation.

COMPUTER VISION & IOT, INTERNSHIP

I built two models in this program. The first one is social distancing detection. I firstly obtained urban drone image dataset from Kaggle and annotated people with CVAT, then I used prepared dataset to train YOLOv5. Final result was the calculation of distance between each person corresponding with drone elevation. The second model is face mask detection which I also used dataset from Kaggle but I trained SSD model from TFOD.

REFERENCES

Available upon request.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

Feb 2019 - Feb 2022

UNIVERSITY OF YANGON

Dec 2014 - Dec 2019

SOUTHEAST ASIAN MINSTERS OF EDUCATION ORGANIZATION

Dec 2017 - Feb 2019

DIPLOMA IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

My passion lead me to the computer science and its infamous sub-branch, Artificial Intelligence.

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN GEOLOGY

I learned all the basics of earth sciences throughout semesters of four.

DIPLOMA IN ENGLISH PROFICIENCY

I have taken numerous courses on six levels of english proficiency.

TRAINING & CREDENTIALS

COURSERA

Specializations, July 2020 - Present

MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEERING FOR PRODUCTION (MLOPS)

Credential ID: 9AGVYPBRNTU3

DEEPLEARNING.AI TENSORFLOW DEVELOPER

Credential ID: F5ZGQ824QGUQ

DEEP LEARNING

Credential ID: YB5FJEBQPBWC

PYTHON 3 PROGRAMMING

Credential ID: PYDF6Z923PQ8

APPLIED DATA SCIENCE WITH PYTHON

Credential ID: H8HDLSL7AMNU